<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Henrique Vicente</title>
    <link>https://henvic.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Henrique Vicente</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://henvic.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts</title>
      <link>https://henvic.github.io/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henvic.github.io/posts/</guid>
      <description>CLI tool software release process Monday, 1 April 2019  Opensource and Go. What license? Monday, 25 February 2019  A Smarter and Better CLI Friday, 23 March 2018  My web development environment  Monday, 16 June 2014   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorites</title>
      <link>https://henvic.github.io/favorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henvic.github.io/favorites/</guid>
      <description>Books Inviting Disaster: Lessons from the edge of technology - James R. Chiles   Normal Accidents: Living with High-Risk Technology - Charles Perrow   The Unix Programming Environment  The Art Of Unix Programming - Eric S. Raymond   Do No Harm: Stories of Life, Death, and Brain Surgery - Henry Marsh   Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship   The Law - Frédéric Bastiat   The Tuttle Twins (books for educating children with a foundation of liberty)    Interesting Go Proverbs   What Every Computer Scientist Should Know About Floating-Point Arithmetic   A Tour of Go  Hypertext Transfer Protocol -- HTTP/1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opensource</title>
      <link>https://henvic.github.io/opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henvic.github.io/opensource/</guid>
      <description>I have created and contributed to many opensource projects. Here is a selected few.
On my portfolio and GitHub profile, you can find more opensource projects.
I created kubeapply is kubeapply is a microservice for running kubectl apply through a web API. Monday, 11 February 2019  ctxsignal is a Go package that can be used to create contexts cancelable by system signals. Friday, 14 September 2018  climetrics is a software used for gathering diagnostics and metrics data for the WeDeploy CLI tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://henvic.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henvic.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Projects with a founder or co-founder label are projects I developed by myself or with a business partner. They include Vehikel, Plifk, to-post.it, and trazqueeupago.com. WeDeploy Command-Line Interface Tool I designed, implemented we in Go, and currently maintain it. I also contributed to other areas of the whole project. Now, WeDeploy is being phased out, and Liferay DXP Cloud is taking its place. The CLI tool is going to stay but is rebranded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://henvic.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henvic.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>Year 2018 Using a Socket.Io Client Implementation for Go  Westside GoLang Meetup Los Angeles, CA Thursday, 12 April 2018   CLI: How can people contribute? WeDeploy&#39;s Retreat, Liferay Tuesday, 23 January 2018    Year 2017 picel - HTTP middleware for image processing (undergraduate project)  UFPE Tuesday, 12 December 2017  Write in Go: The Go Programming Language (slides). Liferay&#39;s Developer Retreat 2017 Thursday, 27 January 2017   Year 2016 Writing a modern CLI tool Liferay Friday, 2 September 2016   Year 2015 Writing CLI tools with Node (slides, notes).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>